Harshavardhan Reddy B

Ø (716) 424-8282 | ■ hbommire@buffalo.edu | in harshavardhan | ♥ Buffalo, NY

Summary

Highly motivated graduate student with six years of professional experience in Software Development leading and delivering complex projects implementing robust features, optimizing performance and scalability with a strong skill set in Java, web technologies and cloud infrastructure.

EDUCATION

University at Buffalo, The State University of New York

Buffalo, New York

Master of Science in Computer Science & Engineering; CGPA: 4/4

Aug 2022 - Dec 2023

o Coursework: Distributed Systems, Database Systems, Data Intensive Computing, Blockchain, Machine Learning, Data Structures & Algorithms, Computer Architecture.

National Institute of Technology, Calicut

Calicut, India

Bachelors in Electronics and Communication Engineering; CGPA: 7.72/10

Jun 2012 - May 2016

EXPERIENCE

Oracle (OCI Data Science)

Bangalore, India

Senior Member of Technical Staff

Apr 2022 - Aug 2022

- Built workflows as a team of 5 to load/unload multiple models with custom ocpus and memory on customer trained models.
- o Brainstormed on Integration of Triton server docker image to reduce latency serving multi model inference requests.
- o Skills: Java11, Python, Data science, SpringBoot, Grafana, Docker, Triton, Gradle, REST API.

JioSaavn

Bangalore, India

Nov 2019 - Apr 2022

Senior Software Engineer

- o Led teams on Digital Rights Management, short videos, audio video content management pipelines.
- Built ground-up products content migration service and archiving pipeline to save costs by 80%.
- $\circ~$ Designed and implemented e2e video pipeline to launch video feature on JioSaavn leading to increased DAU.
- o **Skills**: Java, Golang, ReactJS, SpringBoot, MySql, MongoDB, AWS, Azure, SFTP, Ansible, Kubernetes, Docker, NGINX. **Goodera**Bangalore,India

Senior Product Engineer

Aug 2018 - Oct 2019

- Designed ground-up products spanning centralized authentication, workflow automation and dockerized micro-services for multiple products resulting in 10x faster development.
- o Introduced caching in Grants Management Systems(GMS) resulting in 90% reduced latency.
- Integrated Partners & GMS products to enrich user experience for cross functional features, resulting in increased opportunities for NGOs by 3x.
- o **Skills**: Node.js, Javascript, AngularJS, ReactJS, MySql, MongoDB, AWS, Elasticsearch, Redis, OAuth, Docker, Jenkins. **Netcracker** Bangalore,India

Software Engineer

Jun 2016 - Jul 2018

- Introduced new modules TOE, OM for TOMS product as a part of a 40+ member team, and gained indepth understanding of telecom operations and management solutions.
- Skills: Java8, C++, Javascript, GWT, HTML, CSS, SpringBoot, MySql, Maven, NGINX, SVN, Jenkins.

PROJECTS

- Taco DB: A mini RDBMS in c++, including Buffer Management, Data Layout using Varlen Datapages, Access methods, B-Tree index, query planning, optimization and processing with support for join & aggregation.
- Distributed Systems: Implemented Map/Reduce library, Chandy Lamport algorithm for snapshots and RAFT consensus algorithms for replicated state machine & leader election.
- Weather Change Prediction: Trained dataset with Adaboost, Random Forest, Neural Networks models to predict weather changes and Multi Output Regression models are also developed to predict other disasters.
- New York Cannabis Exchange(Startup): An auction marketplace analogous to eBay Auction Services for Licenced Cultivators and Dispensaries in New York state to buy and sell thier products online. Won first place among 40+ teams for best Spring 2023 Capstone project at University at Buffalo.

Programming Skills

- Languages and Frameworks: Java 17, Node.js, Golang, C++, Python, Spring Boot, JavaScript, ReactJS, AngularJS, HTML, CSS, PHP, Hadoop, Spark.
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, PostgreSQL, Solr, DynamoDB, Elasticsearch.
- Devops & Others: AWS, Azure, Kubernetes, Docker, Ansible, SQS, Git, Maven, Jenkins, Kafka, REST APIs, gRPC.